ALICE MONSAERT: This exercise is what I call an advanced level lunge because the back leg is going to stay straight.
In our regular lunge, we should bend the back knee.
In this exercise, the back leg is going to stay straight while the body moves forward over the forward quadriceps.
So, we're going to do this onto BOSU and incorporate again an upper body exercise along with it.
I like to do a lot of back work because typically our anterior is tight and our back is stretched, so it's nice to have muscle balance and do a lot of back work.
So, the advanced level lunge, I stay up on the toe on the back, get the heel off the floor, keep the legs straight, the knee silently soft, lunge forward, and then come straight.
So, as I lunge, my knees staying over the center of my foot.
If your knee goes past to your toe, then just scoot your back leg forward--or back leg back a little bit, and we're going to incorporate a row.
So, I'm going to lunge, row, and come up.
Lunge forward, row for the back of the shoulders, the lats, or I can change that to incorporate a reverse fly.
So, I'm going to go into that forward advanced level lunge with the back leg is straight, do a reverse fly, and come up.
So, again, my challenge comes from this forward foot being on the unstable surface.
Forward, and one more safety point for you, we never want the spine rounded.
We want it lifted, chest open, and reverse fly.